## RYAN DERN

80 Candlewood Lane, Hanover, MA, 02339 | (781) 424-0773 | ryanmdern@gmail.com

github.com/RMDern

H hackerrank.com/RMDern

## Summary

Motivated computer science student with prior internship experience developing software for highly available, secure, carrier-class telecommunications equipment and cloud deployments.

Technical proficiencies include C++, C, Python, JavaScript, AWS, embedded systems, object-oriented design, mobile development, version control (Git/Perforce), and continuous integration pipelines such as Jenkins.

## Work History

# Software Engineering Intern, Platform Software Sonus Networks, Inc (n/k/a Ribbon Communications) – Westford, MA

11/2017 to 2/2018

- Worked with mentorship from Principal Software Engineers as part of the Platform Software team, developing and maintaining embedded operating system components for carrier-class telecommunications equipment such as session border controllers and media gateways.
- Refactored C/C++ code in use across the product range for performance, security, and maintainability.
- Authored scripts to automate tasks as needed (i.e using grep regular expressions to look for certain instances of pointer member validations in the code base to feed into new static analysis tools).
- Performed development on Unix systems using MobaXTerm. Utilized Perforce, Jenkins, CodeCollaborator.
- Took part in the code review process and iterated on feedback from senior engineers.

### **Electronics Sales Floor Team Member**

06/2015 to 12/2016

Target - Hanover, MA

- Practiced soft skills to regularly maintain 100% satisfaction in customer experience surveys.
- Developed professional communication techniques to succeed in a fast-paced team environment.

#### **Research & Development Project Assistant**

08/2013 to 01/2014

Champlain College - Burlington, VT

- Served as an ambassador at the Career and Internship Fair.
- Collaborated with a small team to assist the office of career services with optimizing their job search and distribution processes. Duties ranged from document preparation to researching potential web scraping solutions.

### Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

University of Massachusetts Boston - Boston, MA

- Completed 85 credits (Junior) towards B.S. (Expected June 2020).
- Cumulative GPA: 3.4, Most Recent Semester GPA: 3.72